<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>All Posts - ziggy&#39;s brain dump</title>
        <link>https://example.com/posts/</link>
        <description>All Posts | ziggy&#39;s brain dump</description>
        <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><copyright>This work is licensed under a Creative Commons Attribution-NonCommercial 4.0 International License.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 22:37:00 &#43;0900</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://example.com/posts/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" /><item>
    <title>BCW: Buffer-Controlled Writes to HDDs for SSD-HDD Hybrid Storage Server</title>
    <link>https://example.com/wang-2020-bcw/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 31 Dec 2020 22:37:00 &#43;0900</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://example.com/wang-2020-bcw/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Short Summary HDDs are under utilized in hybrid cloud storage systems which makes SSD to handle most of the requests. This shorts the life of SSDs and also wasts the utilization of HDDs.
The authors of this paper find that the write requets can have $μ$s-level latency when using HDD if the buffer in HDD is not full. They leverage this finding to let HDD to handle write requests if the requests can fit into the in disk buffer.]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>Read as Needed: Building WiSER, a Flash-Optimized Search Engine</title>
    <link>https://example.com/he-2020-readasneeded/</link>
    <pubDate>Sat, 26 Dec 2020 20:15:00 &#43;0900</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://example.com/he-2020-readasneeded/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[Short Summary This paper proposed a NAND-flash SSD-friendly full text engine. This engine can achieve better performance than existing engines with much less memory requestsed.
They reduce the unnecessary I/O (both the number of I/O and the volume). The engine does not cache data into memory, instead, read data every time when query arrive.
They also tried to increase the request size to exploit SSD internal parallelism.
What Is the Problem Search engines pose great challenges to storage systems:]]></description>
</item><item>
    <title>My First Post</title>
    <link>https://example.com/my-first-post/</link>
    <pubDate>Sun, 08 Nov 2020 09:48:14 &#43;0900</pubDate>
    <author>Author</author>
    <guid>https://example.com/my-first-post/</guid>
    <description><![CDATA[I rebuilt my personal blog by using hugo.
I have cleaned all my old blogs (not so much actually).
I will write something related to my research reading or personal learning. Hope I can meet you soon.]]></description>
</item></channel>
</rss>
